本字幕由YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：装汁的容器    Soomii    红豆包    Iz
校对：Ｊ小糯      时间轴：grace
■
后期：鱼骨头      总监：stephanie
《开心汉堡店》
第一季第十集
■
孩子们  听我说
All right, listen,
从现在起  你们必须好好表现
you kids are gonna be on your best behavior, right now.
我们的房东  费舍奥德先生
The landlord, Mr. Fischoeder's coming over
要来这里谈谈租期问题
to talk about the lease,
不知道他会不会让我们续租
and we don't know if he's gonna renew.
他会的
He'll renew.
可我们有几次没按时交租
Well, we haven't always paid our rent on time.
我们就没按时交过
We never pay our rent on time.
多谢提醒  琳
Thanks, Lin.
听着
All right, listen.
我和你们老妈要去给他做些吃的
Your mother and I are gonna go make him some food.
我们的救命稻草  就是食物和服务
That's gonna save us: our food, and our service.
你们几个现在打扫一下卫生
You kids start cleaning now.
把那个捡起来
Pick that up.
吉恩  你去外面吆喝吆喝  揽些客人
And, Gene, you go outside and try and drum up some business.
我要演奏三角铁
I'll play my triangle!
-不行  -你根本不懂我的音乐
- No! - You don't understand my music!
闭嘴  还有一件事非常重要
Shush. And here's the other important thing:
费舍奥德进门后  你们不许
when Fischoeder gets here, you will not...
强调一遍  不许盯着他看
I repeat, not stare at him
不许闪烁好奇的眼神
like he's some kind of spectacle.
-我不看他  -我从不看他
- I don't stare at him. - I don't ever stare at him.
真不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
没错  费舍奥德先生是个怪人
Yes, Mr. Fischoeder is an eccentric.
他身穿白西服
Yes, he wears a white suit.
头戴独眼罩
And an eye patch.
还开着一辆高尔夫球车到处逛
And he drives a golf cart everywhere.
他就是一只披着羊皮的狼
He is one white cat away from being a super-villain.
可他是这座房子的主人
All right, but he owns this building, everybody.
游乐场也是他的
He owns the amusement park,
差不多城里的一切都是他的
and just about everything else in town,
所以当他进门后  你们不许盯着他看
so you're not going to stare at him when he gets here.
美食来啦
Here we go!
鲍勃  琳达
Bob, Linda,
这帮孩子都不理我
your children are refusing to acknowledge me.
孩子们  别这样
Ah, kids, stop doing that.
立刻向费舍奥德先生打招呼
Acknowledge Mr. Fischoeder, right now.
-你是超级英雄吗  -我可以摸你头发吗
- Are you a superhero? - Can I feel your hair?
停  停  你们几个现在都去打扫卫生
Stop! Stop! Go clean something, now. All of you.
费舍奥德先生
So, uh, Mr. Fischoeder,
我意识到  这么多年来
you know, after all these years,
你从未品尝过我们店的食物
I've realized you've never eaten my food.
现在请允许我献上我们店的特制招牌汉堡
And I want to present to you one of my favorite specialty burgers.
鲍勃  无意冒犯  但我有自我约束
Oh, no offense, Bob, but I have a policy
即  不在租户的家中用餐
that I don't dine at any of my tenants' establishments.
可我见过你在"津津有味寿司店"吃东西
Oh. But I saw you eating at Juicy Sushi.
那个另当别论
That's different.
那家寿司店好吃得不可思议
That place is incredible!
你尝过他们家的海星吗
Have you had their starfish?
入口即化啊
It melts in your mouth.
没人尝过吗  没人吗
No? Nobody?
-你尝过吗  -没有
- You? - No.
话说回来...
Anyway...
这里有点冷清啊
Quiet in here.
每天都这样么  鲍勃
Like this a lot, Bob?
是啊  我是说  这会儿是12点半
Yeah, well, I mean, it's 12:30.
算是餐后休息时间吧
Sorta the lunch lull.
-餐后休息时间  -我们有这么个说法
- The lunch lull. - That's what we call it.
吉米・派丝多的餐后休息时间还真是忙
Jimmy Pesto's lunch lull is really busy.
他们家是卖披萨的
Well, Jimmy Pesto's is a pizza place.
如果你对那货感兴趣  披萨
If you're into that kind of thing... pizza.
二死了
Stupid.
-我喜欢披萨  -披萨  在哪呢
- I like pizza. - Pizza! Where's pizza?
闭嘴
Shush.
当你想吃汉堡的时候...
Anyway, when people want a burger...
极致正宗的美式汉堡...
a good American burger...
别无他选  唯有...
they have nowhere else to go, but...
抱歉  抱歉打断你一下
Sorry. Sorry to interrupt.
跟你说实话吧
Let me be honest with you.
我很欣赏你  鲍勃
I enjoy you, Bob.
你的胡子  令人陶醉
Your mustache, it's fascinating.
谢谢
Thank you.
-不介意我摸一下吧  -你已经在摸了
- Do you mind if I...? - You're touching it.
-没错  我...  -没错  你...
- Yeah. I... - That's... Yeah, you're...
-真的很令人陶醉  -谢谢你
- That's really something. - Thank you.
谢谢你才对
Thank you.
听着  吉米・派丝多想租下这间店铺
Listen, Jimmy Pesto has tendered an offer on this space.
吉米・派丝多  他想搬过来
Jimmy Pesto?! He wants to move over here?!
没错  他想把礼品店搬到这里
Yes, he wants to move his gift shop over here.
礼品店
Gift shop?!
这会是一家很棒的礼品店
This would be an amazing gift shop!
所有圣诞礼物都可以在这里买了
I could do all my Christmas shopping here!
-对啊  -不不不不不不
- Yes! - No, no, no, no, no, no.
拜托  我以为你尝过我的汉堡就会明白
Please, I think if you tried my burger, you'd see that...
老鲍  你总是拖欠房租
Bob, you're always late with the rent,
而吉米总是提前支付
and Jimmy pays early.
等等等等  费舍奥德先生  请等一下
Wait, wait, wait, Mr. Fischoeder, please.
在你做出决定之前
Before you make a decision,
请尝一口我的汉堡  一口就行
just taste my burger. Just taste it.
好吧  还得再去一次健身房
Fine. Another trip to the gym.
吉米・派丝多的生意做得还算可以
Jimmy Pesto may be a good businessman,
不过  你会发现
but I think you'll find that,
和他那些微波炉加工的垃圾不同
unlike his microwaved junk,
我的食物可是...
my food is...
费舍奥德先生  费舍奥德先生
Mr. Fischoeder? Mr. Fischoeder?
他噎住了  他噎
He's choking. He's chok--
-我该怎么办  -快勒他
- How do I do it? - You just push!
-勒哪  -勒他的肚子
- What do I do? - Push on his belly!
顶他的裆部
Hit him in the crotch!
不  吉恩  不能顶裆部
No, Gene! Don't hit him in the crotch.
顶  快顶他的裆部
Yes! Hit him in the crotch!
-我来抓着他的头发  -天啊  天啊
- I'll hold his hair. - Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
-琳达  别添乱了  -天啊
- Linda, please. - Oh, my God!
他的脸变蓝了
Wow! He's turning blue!
把他的手放在热水里
Put his hand in warm water!
他不能死  他不能死在这里
He can't die! He cannot die in here!
那我们快把他抬出去
Let's move him outside.
不  所有人  用手把他围起来
No, everybody, hands around him!
一起把食物勒出来  一  二  三
Group Heimlich! One, two, three!
-出来了  -我勒个擦
- There it is! - Holy crap!
-让开点地方  孩子们  -让开点地方
Give him some room, kids. Give him room!
我说...
So, um...
你觉得味道如何  好吃吗
Did you, uh, did you like it?
你的租约  周五晚到期
Your rent is due Friday night.
如果你拖延
And if you're late,
我就把这间店铺租给吉米・派丝多
I'm giving your lease to Jimmy Pesto.
这个需要打包带走吗
Do you want me to pack this to go?
吃这个还得配些薯条
You're gonna need fries with that.
费舍奥德先生已经没事了
So Mr. Fischoeder is okay...
可是我们必须在明晚前交齐房租
But we've got to pay the rent in full by tomorrow night.
交齐房租
Paying the rent in full!
接下来呢  交齐其他账单吗
What's next? Paying your other bills?
别担心  我们会想些办法的
Don't worry. We'll figure something out.
是吧  鲍鲍
Right, Bobby?
吉米  你妹的  派丝多
Jimmy... freaking... Pesto.
-鲍勃  -派丝多并不是他的真名
- Oh, Bob. - You know, Pesto's not his real name,
他的真名叫波普洛普维奇
It's Poplopovich.
我当然知道  那家伙从里到外都是假的
Of course it is. The guy's a complete phony.
你为什么对他这么痴迷
What is this obsession with him?
我可没痴迷他
I'm not obsessed with him.
你有  你们两个互相痴迷
Yeah, you are. You're both obsessed.
就好像在监视彼此
It's like you guys are stalking each other.
我可以少关注他一些
I could care less about the guy.
你们两个都成熟点行不行
I think you should both grow up,
至少  看在孩子们的份上
at least for the kids' sake.
-让我瞅瞅  让我瞅瞅  -说到孩子
- Let me see. Let me see. - Ugh. The kids.
蒂娜干嘛对小吉米・派丝多死心塌地的
Why does Tina have to like Jimmy Pesto Jr.?
世界上有那么多豆蔻少男...
Of all the 13-year-old boys in the world...
那些少男她也喜欢
Eh, she likes them, too.
还真是浪漫啊
It's kind of romantic, though.
双方家庭交战  爱情从中萌芽
Two families at war, a budding romance...
情节有点像《西区故事》
It's like West Side Story!
百老汇音乐剧
"西区"指曼哈顿西区
-开战  -别玩了
- Rumble! - Stop.
露易丝和那对双胞胎现在也成了朋友
You know Louise is friends with the twins, now, too...
派丝多的两个小儿子  安迪和奥利
Pesto's little boys... Andy and Ollie.
不不不  派丝多家的小孩全都没戏
No, no, no. I'm calling a ban on all the Pesto kids.
这两家的孩子要断绝关系
Our kids are going to cease contact.
-我们来做永远的好朋友吧  -没问题
- Let's be best friends forever. - Okay.
派丝多家双胞胎
我们来割破手掌  然后贴在一起
Let's cut our hands and press them together
-结成拜把兄弟  -赞成
- and become blood brothers! - Okay!
不  结成口水兄弟
No, spit brothers!
把口水吐到手上  然后握手
Spit in your hand and then shake.
两样一起来吧
Let's do both!
不好意思  口水和鲜血我要留着度蜜月呢
Sorry, I'm saving my spit and blood for my honeymoon.
我们一起来蹭蹭眼球吧
Let's rub our eyes together.
-我的红眼病可以传染给你  -好啊
- You can get my pink eye! - Okay!
这年头交朋友好难啊
So hard to be friends these days.
那个自摸全身嗨翻天的人
Hey, is that your brother Jimmy
是你们老哥小吉米吧
touching himself all over?
是啊  他现在很痴迷慢摇舞
Yeah, he's really into slow dancing now.
他知道这种舞是要跟别人一起跳的  是吧
He knows it's supposed to be with other people, right?
是吗
It is?
可怜的蒂娜
Ugh, look at Tina.
和他都接过吻了
Kissed the guy,
可还是无法引起他的注意
and she still can't get his attention.
她应该再叫个胖女孩来跟小吉米3P
She should try pigs in a blanket.
我对这套就招架不住
That always gets my attention.
他又在鼓捣什么幺蛾子呢
Ugh. What's he up to now?
什么  我的天啊
What!? Oh, my God!
棒滋多汉堡  本区最赞  今日起售
"今日起售汉堡"
"Now serving burgers."
汉堡
Burgers!
我受够了  来一决胜负吧
That's it. It's time for a showdown.
太好了
All right.
要开战喽
We're going to a rumble.
我要和他较量一番
I'm gonna confront him.
较量一番
Gonna confront him.
我要把他的脸气歪
Confront him right in the face.
把那张英气逼人的脸气歪
Yeah, right in his handsome face.
-什么  -什么
- What? - What?
你刚才说"英气逼人的脸"
You said "handsome face".
你确实说了
You did.
这...
It's a...
"把那张英气逼人的脸气歪"
"Right in his handsome face. "
我知道我说的是什么
I know what I said.
-你觉得他英气逼人  -逼死我了
- You think he's handsome? - God, yes.
不  我说的是气话
No, I'm saying it with anger,
就像  "你这逼人的帅脸"
like, "You handsome face!"
内涵请自行理解
帅得让人想扁他一顿
He's so handsome you wanna-- you wanna punch him.
他长得像汤姆・塞立克
He looks like Tom Selleck.
美国演员和制片人  大叔脸
我死后  你要将我火化
When I die, I want you to cremate me
然后把我的骨灰撒到汤姆・塞立克的脸上
and throw my ashes in Tom Selleck's face.
-这要求可真疯狂  -我懂的
- That's a crazy request. - I get it.
好了  我们出发
All right, let's go.
孩子们  好好看店
Kids, watch the restaurant.
吉米・派丝多披萨店
棒滋多汉堡  本区最赞  今日起售
要开战喽
-上帝啊  -人真多
- Oh, Lord. - So many people...
孩子们  好好看店
Kids, watch the restaurant.
蒂娜  好好看店
Tina, watch the restaurant.
店店  你自己可以搞定的
Restaurant, we both know you can handle this.
需要时打给我  爱你
Call me if you need me. Love you.
吉米说他马上就来
Jimmy said he'll be right out.
-想尝尝派丝多风情吗  -好啊
- You wanna try a Pesto-colada? - Yeah, sure.
-琳  -怎么了  反正是免费的
- Lin. - What? Free drink.
我擦  你看
Yuck. Look at that.
"追忆似水意面"
"Pasta la vista, baby"?
"弗兰克和泽尔达  银发族美食盛宴"
"Frank and Zelda, oldies with goodies"? Ugh.
goody有"美食  老妇  伪君子"三个意思
有矛盾啊
Some confrontation.
我想整点动静
I want some action.
我需要整些动静出来
I need some action.
小吉米出来了
There's Jimmy Jr.
他连收拾餐桌都那么性感
Busing tables has never looked so sensual.
不就一服务员么
Yet so menial.
吉米出来了  咱就看好戏吧
Here's Jimmy. Now some fur's gonna fly.
原来是汉堡店的鲍勃啊
Bob of Bob's Burgers.
你不就披萨店的吉米・得瑟・派丝多么
Jimmy so-called Pesto of Jimmy Pesto's.
少跟我说好话耍阴招
Let's skip the niceties, shall we?
这位女士  您的派丝多风情
Pesto-colada for the lady.
-免费赠送  -谢谢
- On the house. - Thank you.
这招除外
Except for that nicety.
你跟我耍什么阴招呢  吉米
What are you doing, Jimmy?
抢我的生意  夺我的地盘
Selling burgers, coming after my lease.
你到底想怎样  吉米・波普洛普维奇
What are you doing, Jimmy Poplopovich?
没错  "派丝多"才不是你的真名呢
Yeah, your name is not what it says on the...
琳
Lin.
别喝了
Stop.
真好喝
Ah. It's good.
鲍勃  我这是在做生意
Bob, I run a business, all right?
我不知道你和你的精致原料是要闹哪样
I don't know what you're doing, with your fancy ingredients.
"我是鲍勃  我喜欢蔬菜汤"
"I'm Bob, and I like kale."
-蔬菜汤  -关蔬菜汤什么事
- Kale! - There's nothing wrong with kale.
为什么不管你的店叫"闹心汉堡店"呢
Why don't you call it "Snob's Burgers"?
闹心汉堡店  漂亮
Snob's burgers, ha!
任何没冻坏或腐烂的食物
You think anything that isn't frozen
在你眼里都是精致的么  吉米
or rotten is fancy, Jimmy.
废话少说  徒有其表先生
Okay, Mr. Fancy face,
咱来看看哪家店里有客人
let's see who's got customers?
哎哟  我的店里有一些
Ah, I got some.
咱再看看哪家店里没客人
Let's see who doesn't.
哎哟  你家啊
Oh, you...
我  我家店里有客人的  吉米
I've got... I've got customers, Jimmy.
只不过现在不在而已
They're not there right now.
他们有自己的生活
They have a life.
是么  祝你能在明晚之前凑出房租
Oh, yeah? Well, good luck making rent by tomorrow night.
那我也祝你能用你的"棒滋多汉堡"
Well, good luck trying to steal my customers
成功偷走我的客人
with your Best-o Burger.
他们永远也...  我的妈呀
They'll never... Oh, my God!
-鲍勃  -难以置信
- Bob! - Unbelievable.
我们只是来看球赛的
We just came to watch the ball game.
我只是来上厕所的
I had the urge to sing some journey!
成  琳达  我们走
Come on, Linda, we're leaving!
撤撤  咱也快撤
Go, go. Go, go, go, go.
你休想租到我们的店铺  吉米
You're not going to get our lease, Jimmy!
他肯定会租到这件店铺的
He's going to get our lease.
别想了  鲍鲍
No, Bobby!
忘掉吉米・派丝多吧
Forget about Jimmy Pesto.
我们要做的  就是好好做一天生意
All we need is one really good day of business,
然后交齐房租  保住店铺  是吧
and then we can pay our rent and keep the place, huh?
-是吧  -我想你说得对
- Huh? I guess you're right.
如果明天能招来满满一屋子客人的话
If we could pack the house tomorrow...
肯定能  满满一屋子客人
Sure! A packed house.
我们肯定能做到
We can do that.
大家一起出出主意吧  现在开始
Let's have a family brainstorm, right now.
吉恩  你先来
Gene, go!
现场表演  混合高科技舞曲
Uh, live entertainment featuring a mix of techno...
加上老爸的最爱  三角铁
and dad's favorite, the triangle!
-拉倒  -蒂娜  到你了
- No. - Tina, go!
-慢摇舞  -拉倒
- Slow dancing! - No.
蒂娜  快停下
Tina, stop.
你在干什么  快给我停下
What are you do-- Stop that.
露易丝  你有什么想法
Louise, what do you got?
如果我还年幼无知的话
When I was young and naive,
我会说"放把大火"
I would have said "Arson",
不过我现在要说"伏都巫术"
but I'm gonna go with "Voodoo".
我喜欢放把大火
I like arson.
不  老爸  我认真的  伏都巫术
No. Seriously, dad. Voodoo.
我有一本巫术书  -不行
I have a book. - No.
我真的有本巫术书
No, I have a book!
我去把它拿来
I'll go get it.
有了  做一些半价优惠传单
I got it. Make some flyers
还有只限明晚销售的餐点
for half-off, and good for tomorrow night only.
这样做也许会招些人进来
You know, that might bring some people in.
-是啊是啊  -我找到了
- Yeah, yeah. - Okay, I found it.
别整什么巫术了  我们要做些传单
Forget voodoo. We're doing flyers.
什么  这狗屁主意谁出的  这么没魄力
What? Who's candy-ass idea was that?
我只离开了五秒钟就有人造反啊
I'm out of the room for five seconds!
我们的好主意层出不穷
Ah, we're on a roll.
我们来想点别的吧
Let's brainstorm something else.
圣诞贺卡怎么样
Uh... Christmas card?
不不不  别想了  都已经定了
No, no, no, we're done brainstorming, we got it.
我们把头发剃下来做成圣诞贺卡怎么样
Oh. How about we shave our heads for the Christmas card?
把我们的名字故意拼错
Spell our names wrong.
再剃剃腿毛
Shave our legs.
多么丝滑柔顺的一家人啊
Totally soft, silky family.
这个我喜欢
I like it.
我有本巫术书
I have a book!
大家都别忘记刚才出的主意哦
Nobody forget what they just said.
我去拿些纸过来
I'm-- I'm gonna go get some paper.
当晚打烊后
味道不错嘛
Eh, it's pretty good.
非常不错
It's pretty good.
不错个屁  不错个屁
It's not good! It's not good!
不错个屁
It's not good!
我要把你们都扔掉
Going in the garbage!
如果能整到一撮吉米・派丝多的头发
If I can get a lock of Jimmy Pesto's hair,
我就能控制他的大脑了
I'm pretty sure I can control his mind.
-真的吗  -不知道  我就大概看了下
- Really? - I don't know. I'm just skimming.
我只知道这玩意用在脑残身上特灵验
All I know is it works on fools and imbeciles.
试试我  试试我
Oh, me, me.
你能帮我唤起小吉米
Can you help me dance Jimmy Jr.
答应跟我约会的记忆吗
back into remembering we're going out?
可以啊
Yes, I can.
我只需要一撮你的头发
I just need a lock of your hair.
没问题
Okay.
你能让我在圈内举办一次演奏会吗
Can you help me get a gig in the music business?
拿头发来
Hair.
永别了  老朋友
So long, old friend.
把硬币插进土豆
So if you stick the penny into the potato,
土豆电池
土豆就做成了电池
you've just made a battery out of a potato.
我刚刚用土豆做了一个伏都娃娃
I've just made a voodoo doll out of a potato.
-这谁啊  -我姐姐  蒂娜
- Who is it? - My sister, Tina.
她想让我施法  让你们老哥和她跳慢摇舞
She wants me to make your brother slow-dance with her
让他记得他们约会的事
and remember that they're going out.
你们能整一撮你们老哥的头发给我吗
Can you get a lock of your brother's hair?
可以
Yup.
你还说我随身携带这玩意是脑子有病呢
And you said I was crazy for carrying this around.
看谁现在得意呢  我
Now who's laughing? Me!
-孩子们  学上得怎么样  -很好
- Hi, kids. How was school? - Good.
老妈  安迪和奥利来帮我做份作业
Mom, Andy and Ollie are helping me with a school project.
我需要15个土豆
I'm gonna need 15 potatoes,
还要一撮你和老爸的头发
a lock of hair from you and dad.
如果有朗姆酒和雪茄烟  那就更好了
Also rum and cigars, if you have any.
-等等  这些玩意用来干嘛  -学英语
- Wait. What's this for? - English.
你们俩有家庭作业吗
You two have homework?
-有一点  -我不想做
- A little. - Not doing it.
很好  因为你俩得去码头发传单
Good. Cause you're going down to the pier to hand out flyers.
我们回来了
We're back.
全都发完了吗
Did you pass 'em all out?
是啊  我们救了这个家
Yup. We saved the family.
连吉米・派丝多都拿了一张
Jimmy Pesto even took one.
独翅吉米也拿了一张
So did Jimmy-One-Wing.
那是一只海鸥
He's a seagull I met.
搞什么鬼名堂
What the hell?
仅限今晚
凭对家店铺的传单
享受本店半价优惠
"还有免费T恤等着您哦"
"Plus a free T-shirt"?
苍天啊
Oh, my God.
莫特带他妈妈来吃饭了
Aw, Mort's bringing his mother to dinner.
不  不  不
No. No. No!
他们是我的客人
Those are my customers!
我要下挑战书  即刻开战
This is a war now. This is a war.
听  这是《勇敢的心》主题曲
Listen, it's the theme from Braveheart!
-别闹了  -等等等等
- No! - Wait, wait.
这块是最精彩的部分
This is the best part...
老爸  你在干嘛
Dad, what are you doing?
吉恩  蒂娜  别出声
Shh! Gene, Tina,
这也许是最后一次拯救餐馆的机会
this may be our last chance to save the restaurant.
你们的父亲现在需要集中精力
Your father needs full concentration right now.
他正在尝试人世间最难做的汉堡
He's attempting to make the most difficult burger known to man.
我就见他成功过一次
I've only seen him do it once successfully.
现在  他得把这种汉堡做成迷你试吃品
And now he has to do it in a mini sampler size.
那是什么
What is it?
什锦肉堡
He calls it "the meatsiah".
汉堡胚内夹上一块鞑靼牛肉
It's beef tartare inside a burger,
煎至五分熟  再夹入惠灵顿汉堡胚
medium-well inside a burger Wellington.
老爸会死吗
Is dad gonna die?
也许会  宝贝儿  也许会
Maybe, honey, maybe.
他对那块一定很满意
Oh, he has to be happy with that one.
这东西怎么会拯救餐馆呢
So how is this gonna save the restaurant?
我要穿上那件汉堡装
Am I gonna put on the burger suit
站在门前发汉堡吗
and hand these out in front?
不  我们要把这些汉堡拿到战场上去
Oh, no. We're going straight to the source with these.
你是得站在门前发汉堡
You're gonna be handing these out
不过是站在吉米・派丝多的门前
in Jimmy Pesto's restaurant.
没错  就是这样
That's right, whoa.
今晚  这些试吃品将会换来我们的房租
These samples are gonna get us our rent money tonight,
这样我们就能保住这间店铺了
so we can keep this place.
免费的试吃品怎么换钱啊
How are free samples gonna get us money?
他们吃完试吃品
They'll try the samples,
就会爱上它们
and they'll love 'em,
然后他们就还想吃  还想吃
but they'll want more, more!
他们会狂热地追求这些汉堡
They'll be craving these burgers,
得不到心里就痒痒
itching to get their fix!
就像吸海洛因
Like heroin.
-没错  儿子  就像吸海洛因  -太好了
- That's right, son, like heroin! - Yes!
但是我们得同心协力  互相配合
But this family's gonna have to execute perfectly
才能赢得这场战争
to pull this off.
露易丝哪去了
Where's Louise?
这位要举办处女演奏会
This one shall have his first gig.
这位要贴着那位大跳慢摇舞
This one shall slow dance upon that one.
吉米・派丝多先生的命运仍悬而未决
And Mr. Jimmy Pesto's fate is yet undetermined,
因为我还需要一些他的头发
because I still need to get some of his hair.
我现在就去整点  想一起来吗
I'm gonna go get it right now. Wanna come?
-我们想待在这里  -永远
- We want to stay here. - Forever.
我们想待在这里  永永远远
We wanna stay here forever and ever.
-我们想葬在此处  -葬在此处
- We want to be buried here! - Buried here!
好吧  等我回来后就把你们埋在这里
Okay, I'll bury you when I get back.
你要用头发当捐献品
You're taking hair donations?
没错
That's right.
为了那些患上胡癌的人
Hm, for people with mustache cancer?
对  这是一种很严重的病
Yeah, it's a serious disease.
你是鲍勃的女儿吧
Hey, aren't you Bob's kid?
不是  怎么可能
No! No, no.
爸爸  弗兰克和泽尔达吃完烤明虾后
Dad, Frank and Zelda both got the scampi,
在厕所里大吐特吐呢
and now they're in the bathroom puking.
看在上帝的份上
Oh, for God's sake.
这会儿我上哪整钢琴师去啊
Where am I gonna get another piano player at this hour?
我们可以放"从男孩到男人"的歌
We could put on some Boyz II Men
然后我来跳慢摇舞
and I could slow dance.
小胡椒  我说了一千遍了  不行
Hey, pepper, no! For the thousandth time, no!
这是我的挚爱  爸爸  我的挚爱
It's my passion, dad! Passion!
我倒是认识一个人
I know a guy.
你好  开心汉堡店
Hello, Bob's burgers.
你有没有告诉老爸你的行踪
You tell dad where you were going?
他正在做迷你汉堡呢
Mm, he's working on his burger bites.
那里有一套架子鼓  给我捧个场
Hey, there's a drum set. Back me up!
抱歉  还得过一会儿
Sorry, it'll just be another minute.
后厨真的非常忙
We're really backed up in there.
吉恩实现梦想了  伏都娃娃生效了
Gene got his wish! The voodoo is working!
你好吗  T恤不错哦
How you doing? Nice shirt.
天啊  吉恩的公开表演处女秀
Oh, my God! Gene's first public performance!
汉堡已经差不多了  都准备好了吗
These are almost done. Is everybody ready?
哎哟  我家蒂娜在跳舞呢
Aw! And my Tina's dancing.
我的小蛤蜊从她的贝壳里钻出来了
My little clam's coming out of her shell!
我就出去一小会儿
I'm just gonna slip out for one sec!
好了  咱们走
Okay, here we go.
赢回餐馆的时刻到了
Time to go win back the restaurant!
琳达  孩子们
Linda? Kids?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
这件汉堡装本应该是吉恩穿的
Gene was supposed to wear the costume.
知道吗  我要亲自上阵
Well, you know what? I'll do this myself.
下面是一首慢拍曲
This next number's a slow jam.
名叫"三线不成方"
It's called "Three sides don't make a square."
谢谢
Thank you.
怎么  你脑子进水了么
What happened, did you snap?
徒有其表先生是来逛妓院的么
Did Mr. Fancy face take a trip to the sexy store?
-不  -这件汉堡装穿在你身上小了点
- No. - It's a little small on you.
泡菜那一层有点紧是吧
A little tight in the pickles, huh?
托盘里是什么
What's on the tray?
是迷你汉堡  吉米
These are burger bites, Jimmy.
人世间最好的汉堡
The best in the world.
我要让你的客人们见识见识真正的美食
I'm gonna show your customers what real food is.
来尝尝真正的汉堡  先生
Here, try a real burger, sir.
那我走这边
I'm gonna go this way then.
-不不不  -好吧  那我就...
- Nah-nah-nah. - Yeah. Well, then I'm...
少戳我
Don't poke me.
真正的汉堡  就在街对面
Real burgers. Right across the street.
滚开
Just move.
Eh, just move.
-闭...  什么  -不是我干的
- Shut... what? - I didn't do it.
没错  是我干的
Yeah, I did it.
-不是吧  -那是老爸吗
- Oh, no. - Is that dad?
你们几个
And you people!
叛徒  你们几个叛徒
Traitors! Traitor family!
这可是吉恩的处女秀
It's Gene's first public performance!
老爸  要算账就在地下室算
You could had me at the ground floor, dad.
现在  我要演奏"大房子"了
Now I play "The big rooms".
你得让孩子们乐呵乐呵
You gotta let the kids have a little fun.
我们不乐呵么  琳达
We have fun, Linda!
我们一直都很乐呵
We have lots of fun!
他穿的那是什么
What's he wearing?
-我的汉堡胚  -背后多出一些的汉堡胚
- My buns. - With a few extra buns hanging out the back.
老爸  我在打鼓
Hey, dad, I'm playing drums!
真高兴能见到你打鼓  露易丝
Oh, I'm so happy you're playing drums, Louise!
我建议你
And you know what?
你应该把自家的小怪胎们关在自家院子里
You should keep your freaky kids locked up in your own place.
你说我的孩子是什么
What did you say about my kids?
给他那英气逼人的裆部来一脚
Hit him in his handsome groin!
-等一下  -小心点
- Wait. - Watch it.
你...  我要...
You... I'm gonna...
等等  等等
Wait. Wait.
拿下他  老爸
Get him, dad.
来呀  来呀
Come on! Come on!
别担心  老爸
Don't worry, dad!
拿下没有  拿下没有
Anything? Anything?
试吃品我拿着呢  鲍鲍
I got the samples, Bobby.
糟了
Aw, crap.
这两个傻子
That looks silly.
来收房租吗
Come for the rent?
-是啊  我来收房租  -鲍勃
- Yes, I've come for the rent. - Bob!
别喊  让他们打吧
No, no, let 'em fight.
我过去打个赌
Looks like a betting crowd.
谁押汉堡男输  赔率三比一
Who wants three-to-one against the burger?
我
Right here!
我看看  我看看
Yeah, let me see. Let me see.
这是你的份儿
You wanna... Here... Oh!
好了  是平局
All right, it's a draw.
谁押了"他们最后拥抱彼此入怀"
Who had "They end up hugging each other"?
-我  -给你十块
- Me. - That's ten to you.
谢谢
Thank you.
好了  鲍勃  吉米
Now, Bob, Jimmy,
一起去吉米的礼品店吧
let's all go over to Jimmy's new gift shop--
抱歉  我是说  鲍勃的汉堡店
I mean... sorry, Bob's place,
边喝美酒边把这事解决了  好吗
and settle this over some nice alcohol, hmm?
鲍勃
Bob...
房租准备好了没
do you have the rent?
没有  还差一点
No. Not all of it.
好  那这样吧
Okay then. Here we go.
-神啊  -把你的手给我
- Oh, God. - Give me your hands.
好吧
Uh... sure.
你很爱哭吗
Do you cry easily?
偶尔吧
Um... sometimes.
很好  我们现在就来做个了结
Well, let's get it over with.
鲍勃  我不会再把这件店铺...
Bob, I will not be renewing...
好香  这是什么味
Oh, what is that amazing smell?
-有人饿了吗  -那是什么
- Who's hungry?! - What are those?
盛在圣盘上的  什锦肉堡
Only the holy grail of hamburgers... the meatsiah!
这汉堡...  防噎吗
Are these... choke-resistant?
一口就进肚
They're bite-sized!
那好
Oh, good.
我从来...
I have never...
没吃过...
eaten a burger...
这么...
half...
快踢他裆部
Hit him in the crotch!
我开玩笑的
I'm just kidding.
这么美味的汉堡  太好吃了
As good as this. This is great!
这种感觉很难以言传
Yeah! Oh, it's-it's complicated.
有一点点神秘  还有一点点野性
It's-it's mystical, it's-it's barbaric...
谢谢
Thank you.
费舍奥德先生  我本想...
Mr. Fischoeder, I wanted to...
-我还没说完呢  吉米  -我本想...
- I'm talking, Jimmy. - I wanted to...
听我说完
I'm talking.
鲍勃  你也许是我遇到过的最烂的租户
Bob, you might be the worst tenant I've ever had,
连养浣熊的我都租过  他们都比你好
and I rent space to a raccoon sanctuary.
我知道  他们就在隔壁
I know. They're next-door.
我正想跟你谈一下...
I've been meaning to talk to you about....
-不用说了  -好吧
- Shh. It's okay. - Right.
我明白了  你那天就想告诉我
I get it now. You were trying to tell me the other day,
可我听不进去  因为我当时快被噎死了
but I wouldn't listen because I was choking to death.
费舍奥德先生
Mr. Fischoeder...
吉米  拜托  别说了
Jimmy, please! Please!
我当时正在思考我的人生
I was thinking about my life, you see,
我是多么不想
and how I didn't want it to end
在你这寒酸的小餐馆那又脏又破的地板上
in your pathetic little restaurant
结束我的一生
on your sad, filthy floor.
可是现在我明白了
But now I see it.
你不是商人
You're not a businessman.
你在乎的不是客人和利润
You don't care about customers and money!
不  我在乎  很在乎
No, I do. I do.
不  你是一个艺术家  一个牛肉艺术家
No, no, you are an artist... a beef artist.
一个放屁艺术家
A be-fartist! A poet!
be-fartist音似beef artist
一个颂扬牛肉  面包  和泡菜的诗人
Who writes with meat and buns and pickles
你就是油肚肥肠  异性恋版的惠特曼啊
like a greasy, heterosexual Walt Whitman.
美国诗人  代表作《草叶集》
谢谢夸奖
Uh... thank you.
费舍奥德先生  我...
Okay. Well, Mr. Fischoeder, I...
-吉米  -这不公平...
- Jimmy! - No, it's fair...
吉米
Jimmy!
别说了
Please.
-接下来要说的是  -就因为我不肥
- Which brings me to your lea... - Just 'cause I'm not greasy...
闭嘴
Shut up!
接下来要说的是你的租约问题
Which brings me to your lease.
我决定让你续约
Let's extend it!
太好了  老鲍
All right, Bobby!
但是以后要按月收费
But I gotta make it month-to-month.
好吧
Um... all right.
-我们接受  -我还要加点租金
- We'll take it. - And I have to raise your rent a little.
好吧  就这么说定了
Okay. That's... yes.
爸爸
Daddy!
安迪  奥利  你们在这做什么
Andy, Ollie, what are you doing here?
-作法  -什么玩意儿
- Voodoo! - What?
作法
Voodoo!
没错  我们还互换了内裤
Yeah, and we switched underpants!
奥利  那是秘密
Ollie, that was a secret!
我忍不住了
I couldn't hold it in anymore!
等等  他们是你的孩子吗
Wait. These are your kids?
你还有脸说我的孩子是怪胎
And you thought my kids were freaky?
孩子们  我们走
Come on, boys, we're leaving.
不嘛  我们想留下来
No! We wanna stay!
对呀  这可好玩儿了
Yeah, it's fun here!
说的好  吉米  这可好玩儿了
Yeah, Jimmy. It's fun here.
闭嘴
Shush.
好咧  我们来庆祝吧
All right! Let's celebrate!
好耶
Yes!
吉恩  赏个脸行吗  给我们来点音乐吧
Gene? Ah, do us the honor. A little music?
你对我有信心了
You believe in me.
三角铁上场
Time to tickle the iron.
慢摇舞
Slow jam.
走吧  小吉米  我们回去干活儿了
Come on, Jimmy Jr., let's get back to work.
不  爸爸
No, dad!
我要和翠西跳舞
I'm gonna dance with Tracy!
-蒂娜  -和蒂娜跳舞
- Tina. - Tina!
看来巫术起作用了
Yup, voodoo works.
我简直是神
I'm a God!
我跳得对吗  有没有很性感  莫特
Am I doing this right? Mort, do I look sexy?
我的裤子快掉下来了  有没有  莫特
My pants aren't falling down, are they, Mort?
当我跳起舞  有时裤子会掉下来
When I dance, sometimes my pants fall down.